Go go gadget, Bug Bunny. Exact Did that
fly over your head? Did Have you did you
know what Inspector Gadget is? No no, I
know what Dude,
I know what Inspector
You're asking me whether I know what
Inspector Gadget is. Of course I know
what Inspector Gadget is.
I grew up watching like I Love Lucy and
stuff, so I don't know I don't know what
people know.
Do do do do do do do do Inspector Gadget
do
Hey guys, real quick, I just wanted to
do a shout-out to the Hacker Content
Team. Uh they've been doing an awesome
job with us recently helping with the
social media management side and uh sort
of taking the load off of me so I can
focus on delivering awesome content for
you guys. Um so if you think your
organization as well could benefit from
some hacker-oriented social media
management help, then Hacker Content is
the number one place to get it. Um and I
highly recommend them. So head over to
hackercontent.com to send in an inquiry.
Uh and if you mention the podcast when
you do, you'll get your first month of
social media management stuff free.
Um so yeah, check that out. All right,
back to the pod.
Dude, oh my gosh, this is clutch. Bagel
is Bagel, Joel's cat is literally
hugging the mic right now. It's so cute.
Oh my gosh. What a sweet little cat.
Dude, all right. Well, you flexed on me
with the cat. Now I'm going to flex on
you
with this beautiful Caido sweater I'm
wearing right now. Do you see this?
so jealous. Where did you get that?
So actually,
this one's yours actually.
So the Caido team was like, "Hey, we'll
send you some sweaters." And I'm like,
"Hell yeah, send them both to me."
Oh, wow.
And uh and I already spilled coffee on
mine, so I'm wearing I'm wearing yours
today
um Damn.
for this lovely podcast recording. So
shout-out to the Caido team. Thanks for
that awesome uh
awesome gift. I will wear it with pride
often and I will never give Joel's
back to him.
I'm moving to the East Coast soon, so
you're going to have to give it to me.
That's true. You're going to You're
going to come and get it. Um all right,
man. Let's hit the news real quick and
then we'll get into today's topic, which
is gadgets that you need to be on the on
the lookout for when you're doing some
web pen testing. And we have
Let's see, 17 it looks like gadgets that
kind of get the get the gears turning a
little bit, um
which is awesome. And I'm really excited
for this episode because I think there's
a lot of a lot to be gained from this.
And even just from me sitting down and
you know, formulating this this topic
and this content, I've kind of benefited
from it because I think a lot of my
hunting is just intuition-based and I
can't really explain why I know what I
know about hacking. It's just a part of
like my development uh you know, a a
part of who I am, a part of spending a
bunch of time and understanding what
stuff is weird and what stuff is not
weird. Um
but then and so when somebody tries to
explain it to you or or ask them to
explain it,
someone ask you to explain it to them,
it gets a little bit tricky because it's
like, "How do I
how do I put this into words?" Well,
this is how you put it into words. So
hopefully hopefully I'll do justice to
that later today and uh and that should
be a a pretty good piece of content for
this episode.
Um for sure.
All right. So first, since we already
talked about Caido, let's just go ahead
and mention Caido again. Have you
noticed that Caido is like
blowing up recently?
Yeah, and they're putting out really
good features. Um literally just
yesterday they came out with a couple
new features, things that I've been
asking about as well. Um so one specific
thing is they made
um HTTPQL,
which is their query language they call
it basically. But it's you know, it's
basically kind of like Wireshark-esque
way to um query and search through
requests. Well, by default it was only
in the that search tab or the logging
tab or whatever it's called.
And I had a big complaint that, you
know, essentially that made it very
difficult with HTTP uh the HTTP history
tab where you have to switch context
between the search tab and your history
tab. You don't have the same kind of
filtering and all that kind of stuff.
And so finding requests very difficult.
And so finally, they made it so HTTPQL
uh one supports regex, huge. But two is
enabled in the HTTP history tab. Heck
yeah.
So um that was one of the really big
features that I was super psyched about.
Um it's made sort of the flow a lot
easier.
Um the other
big thing that came out recently, and I
don't know if we talked about this, but
they just um you know, while we were in
Miami actually, um they released a
customization feature. So you can now
load custom CSS and JavaScript into your
Caido instance Dude, that's um to
customize it, to change themes, to add
tabs, to do all sorts of things.
Basically anything you can do in the UI
through JavaScript and CSS, you can do
it
through through these custom uh files
that you can load. And I didn't know
about this until yesterday, but I was
chatting with the Caido team and I was
like, "Hey, you know, is there any
possibility for some such and such
feature?" And they were like, "No, not
yet, but there is a thing in um even
better,
which does this." And I was like, "What
is that?" Yeah.
And sure enough, Bebex Bebexor Our boy
Bebex. Yeah, Bebex.
He wrote this open-source um you know,
essentially CSS and and JavaScript that
you put in your Caido called even better
uh that are designed to increase some of
the functionality and features within
Caido um taking advantage of that
JavaScript and CSS. And it's really
awesome. It adds a bunch of cool
features like being able to export scope
and import scope um
and change theme and and a couple other
things. So uh it it adds
a CSRF uh support, you know, through
Bebex's CSRF tool, which is very similar
to Burp Collaborator. Mhm. Um so there's
a lot of really cool stuff in there. Um
we'll put a link down in the description
to even better. But you know, make sure
you know, if you haven't hopped on the
Caido train yet, It's
it's leaving the station. So
the station, man. No, it absolutely is.
And I have heard, I will say, I have
heard rumors of the price change uh that
may occur within the next X amount of
time. So, you know, if you haven't
bought your year subscription now, go
ahead and do that. And don't forget to
use the CTBB podcast discount code to
get an extra 10% off um before they
raise the price. So, maybe I shouldn't
have said that for the Caido team, but
you know, whatever.
Well, I mean, what I'll say is from I
don't know when or how it's going to
change, but I will say from like the
user perspective, they sent out a survey
asking everybody who uses Caido, "What
do you think of the pricing? What would
you pay for this?" Blah blah. So they're
they're definitely considering whether
or not their pricing is in line with
sort of what people are thinking and
what they're thinking in terms of a
profit model. So
Yeah. Um you know, it's always better to
buy in early, right? So Absolutely. And
it was it was nice that
it it was it was nice that they they
had, you know, the the pro tier being a
little bit cheaper during this period of
development and growth. But now they're
really especially with the ability to um
add JS and CSS and then also the ability
shortly to have uh passive workflow
checks and that sort of thing where
we're actually starting to be able to
build out our own automation inside of
Caido, that's when it's really going to
be like, "Okay, this is 100% you know,
the go-to uh product." And I think
that's, you know, probably weeks to one
or two months away. Um so we're we're
really getting close to that point at
this
at this point. And uh and I'm really
excited as well to see what's going to
happen as soon as people start uh um my
phone's going off. As soon as people
start developing um plugins for this
thing because I imagine it's going to
blow up. And we need some we need to to
transfer some plugins over from Burp,
100% um But as soon as we can do that, I
think it's it's really going to bring,
you know, bring it to the next level.
Yeah, so a couple things on that that I
will say. Um so one, uh
I
I totally agree. Like I think now is a
great time um to get on. Like probably
for the for the last, you know, whatever
how long I've been using Caido,
um it has been a little bit of sort of a
you know, I'm paying for it mostly out
of support, but it's not quite in a
fully usable ready to hack on state. You
know, it was it was it was pretty good,
especially in the last couple months. Um
but early on, it was it was not quite
there in terms of comparing to Burp.
This last I hack event, I used Caido
exclusively. I know a bunch of other
hackers did. Um and I know that they
passed along their a lot along their
feedback over to the Caido team. And
that stuff has been actioned on very
quickly. Myself included. Like I I was
taking notes during the whole last I
hack event using Caido as my main proxy.
Um I took, you know, "Hey, this thing
works in Burp. This thing doesn't work
in Caido. Uh can we work on fixing
that?" Hey, this is a real pain point
that I'm used to in Burp, but it's very
difficult to do this or impossible to do
this in Caido. Can we work on fixing
that? And they were very very quick
about, you know, "Yep, we'll work on
this. We'll work on this." Blah blah. Um
and it it's very apparent that uh
they're they're now like at a point
where it's essentially one-to-one
comparable with Burp, especially with
even better, right? Like one of the big
things was lack of collab. Well, now
there's a startup sheriff type support
with a Bebex tool. So that's huge. Or
you can use interact uh
interact uh SH from Project Discovery
and you can spin up your own interaction
server and just do it that way if you
want. Yeah. Um so there's there's
definitely a lot of possibilities now,
which is really really awesome to see.
One thing Um and I think it's only going
to go up. What one thing that that I
noticed that they did in this last
version was they said changes to the
free users and then they they limited
the number of projects that they're
allowed to have and the number of uh
workflows that they're allowed to have,
which I thought was kind of interesting.
But then they also enabled the
JavaScript shell convert nodes for
free users, which I thought was a really
interesting choice because like, you
know, they're moving their model a
little bit away from this free tier and
trying to be like, "Hey guys, could you
actually support the project because
like,
you know, we need to get some support
running for this."
You know, it cuz it needs to be
sustainable for them. I mean, that these
guys are doing it full-time and they've
been working on it for a while now.
But, I also thought it was a nice
little, you know, bone that they they
threw to the free users to actually give
them access to the JavaScript and shell
nodes to let them implement their own
sort of convert workflows if they want
to,
which which I think is I think that's a
a kind move. Yeah, and I and I love
those specific nodes. I was messing with
them yesterday cuz they had they did
some changes to the workflow stuff. And
you know, I one of my one of the tools
and plugins that I've been using a lot
recently is the Google protobuf
extension that was created by uh
extension that was created by um Sam Erb
and a couple of other people over at
Google. And you know, basically what it
does is it just
funnels raw protobuf data into this tool
called protoscope that you know, will
decompile it into the field IDs and
whatnot. And um
I made a basically a little convert
workflow that calls that for me from
Caido. So instead, you know, I was able
to do it from Burp natively with tabs
and stuff. It's not quite as clean yet
cuz there's no
plugin tabs and stuff like that. Like
it's not really built in, but I can
highlight the data, right click,
convert, select my workflow, and it just
will either decode it or encode it. And
it's it's really nice. It lets me work
with protobufs easier in Caido. You
know, that's again one of those things
that is a tricky thing coming from Burp
where there's an extension that just
kind of natively, you know, goes and it
makes it nice.
And trying to find a way to do that in
Caido
is still a little tricky, but the one
thing I will say,
another recent update was that they
fixed upstream proxies. So, I find
myself using both Caido and Burp at the
same time now lately just for some some
of those edge cases as I'm in that
transition where I'll send stuff to Burp
and then have or sorry, send stuff to
Caido, have Caido send it to Burp. If I
can't do something in Caido, I go to
Burp and I mess with the request there.
And then eventually I will hopefully
phase Burp out. Yeah, especially when
we've got these, you know, monster
machines that that are are used to
having to run Burp at like scale, you
know, and then we just, you know, have
Caido sort of in the front now. And and
so, I I think
I have a laptop now that I just used to
run Caido normally. You know, it can't
really run Burp because it's not as as
chunky, but it's light and it's, you
know, 14 14-in screen and stuff like
that. So, that's great.
But yeah, in the in the transition
period, having those chunky desktops,
throwing Caido in front of it is really
not going to do anything for it. So, you
know, it's definitely a good way to
transition. I also saw it in one of
these little chats we're in, Sam Erb
said the second they have a plugin
support, I'm going to write this
protobuf tool into Caido, which is super
awesome to see. I love people, you know,
saying that they're going to be ready to
to tackle that whenever it comes out.
Yeah, so so
I don't know if we can say this, but but
I'm going to say it.
Rez asked the team, "Hey, any updates on
like plugins, languages, that kind of
stuff?" Sounds like plugins are going to
be mostly JavaScript just like the just
like the nodes. Um so, if you're a
plugin developer or you're really
passionate about a certain plugin and
it's not written in JavaScript cuz I
don't think any of the Burp plugins are,
unfortunately. They're going to be Java
or Python Jython.
Now is probably a good time to start
considering, you know, maybe writing it
into node
or JavaScript to some extent or make it
callable from JavaScript somehow. Even
if it's like a wrapper around like
calling Python underneath of the hood,
you could probably do a hacky like that.
But, you know, something to consider if
you want to be one of those plugin devs
that's right on the front
of the Caido sort of plugin chain.
Maybe maybe get ahead of that a little
bit. Yeah, that's a that's a great
point. I think Beba has already done a
great job of that, but there's anytime
there's an emerging technology like this
that that
a lot of the top players in the industry
are saying, "Hey, this is going to be
the thing." Um
there's a big opportunity for anyone who
wants to make a name for themselves in
the dev arena to to jump on that and be
an early adopter and and get your
plugins, you know, to the forefront of
the that sort of scope.
So, definitely definitely a lot of cool
opportunities there. The JavaScript
choice I think is pretty solid. I I
think JavaScript is one of the most
versatile languages and I've actually
been kind of talking to friends about
like, "Hey, what what kind of language
should I learn if I want to learn
scripting stuff right now?"
You know, just be able to write exploits
and stuff like that. And I was, you
know, of course my go-to was like, "Oh,
you should learn Python. Python's the
[__] Like I love Python." But after,
you know, putting a little bit more
careful consideration into it, if you're
really trying to just perform well
in the hacking arena, JavaScript's the
way to go because you need to know
JavaScript inside out, upside down to be
able to do web hacking. Um and so,
you're going to have to learn it
already. Uh and then so, you might as
well just kind of take that extra little
bit to learn the node piece and be able
to write it on the server side and you
know, be familiar with the syntax and
that sort of thing.
So, yeah, I like I like that decision by
the team to to to use JavaScript. I
think that'll be a good long-term
choice.
Yeah, for sure.
Um cool. You want to talk about
NahamSec and all that kind of fun stuff?
Couple couple Naham Con things or
NahamSec related.
Couple Naham things.
Uh
we have we have a really cool tweet that
went out by by Ben
yesterday and it was essentially saying,
"Hey, I'm introducing a five-week
program, a program designed to help you
find your first vulnerability. At the
end of the five weeks, I will bring
someone onto my team to work directly
with me on a pen test." So, essentially
what he's offering here is a like a boot
camp of sorts is what it looks like
running his Discord. Um
and
after those five weeks, you know, the
belle of the ball or whatever will be
selected and that they'll get the chance
to work with NahamSec on a on a pen
test,
which is super awesome.
And I think it's a great opportunity for
anyone who's trying to really like
turbo power their entry into the
industry. You know, being able to say,
"Hey, I went through this boot camp and
I,
you know, went and and worked with
NahamSec on a pen test." That's an
awesome resume.
So, definitely check that out if any of
you guys are interested in that. It's a
little bit more beginners oriented, so I
imagine most of our audience would not
be super interested in this, but
for the any of any of you crazy
beginners out there that still try to,
you know, wade through the weeds of this
podcast, then this could be something
interesting for you.
Yeah, for sure. I think it's a great
opportunity to sort of build some really
really awesome connections within within
the industry and within the bug bounty
scene and you know, make a name for
yourself. Like if
if you feel like you're someone who has
the skills and has the abilities, like
go for it. Absolutely. There's nothing
stopping you. What's the what's that
quote? You miss 100% of the shots you
don't take. So,
you know, go take the shot and you know,
show show everybody what you got.
That's my
it's my shooting the shot noise.
Do you like that? Yeah, thanks.
Like a little spitball.
Dude, you know what's really this is
totally not related to hacking, but um
you know what's really interesting in
languages is the
uh
the sounds that you make for things that
you like, you know, rain or something
like that. Pitter-patter, pitter-patter,
pitter-patter. In Japanese, it's za. Za.
And like and they all change, you know,
across different languages that I
imagine. You know, like every every you
know, language has a certain I wonder if
it has to do with like the building
materials that each sort of society was
using as as like languages being
developed. You know, like tin roofs
versus like Oh, yeah. straw or you know,
like that kind of stuff. Huh. I I didn't
I never thought about that. I'm sure
there's so many variables that go into
that, but anyway, I'm sorry. Bringing it
back to the bringing it back to the the
hacking stuff. Last announcement, your
boys are hosting NahamCon this year.
That's right. Rhino Raider, Techno Geek,
we're going to be hosting that [__] So,
it's going to be awesome.
It's going to be Dude, that's going to
be a long day, man. It's going to be a
long day of really awesome technical
content being
you know, on display at NahamCon. I'm
super looking forward to it.
Absolutely. And those dates I think are
I want to say May 20-something, 23rd,
24th, 23rd, 25th. Let me pull it up
really quick. I'm not actually sure if
that's released yet. So, we may need to
to bleep that, but
Okay. That That's That's good. Well,
whatever it is, we'll put it in the
description and you guys can check it
out. I think yeah, May 24th and 25th. He
did He did tweet it out. So, we're good
to keep it. May 24th, May 25th, we're
going to be hosting it. It's going to be
awesome. So, definitely put that on your
calendars and keep an eye on
Ben's tweets to get more details on
that.
Yeah, absolutely. All right, man.
The time has come
for
gadgets. Go go gadget bug bounty. Exact
Did that fly over your head? Did Have
you Did you know what Inspector Gadget
is? No, no, I know what Inspector
I know what Inspector
You're asking me whether I know what
Inspector Gadget is. Of course I know
what Inspector Gadget is. I grew up
watching like I Love Lucy and stuff, so
I don't know I don't know what people
know.
Do do do do do do Inspector Gadget.
Yeah.
So, yeah.
We are about to become Inspector Gadget
for bug bounty right now. We're going to
talk about all these awesome gadgets.
I don't know, Joel, take a look at some
of these and we can we don't even have
to do this in order. That's how crazy we
are right now.
Um
What do you Do Do you see any one in
particular that you like that we should
start off with or should we just hit
start from the top?
Let's see. Let's Let's Let's start off
with the surprising one here actually.
HTML injection. Okay, now HTML injection
gets like a lot of hate, right? And it
does.
I think like the theme of this whole
episode is really like um
you know, it's it's about gadgets. But
what does that mean, right? Like gadgets
I think what we're referring to here is
like things
um that as a hacker you notice like
little tidbits and parts of the
application and behaviors
um that you can often chain together or
turn into something more impactful. So,
for HTML injection, like what can you do
with that? Well,
DOM clobbering is is like a great place
to start. Um you know, I think depending
a lot on the attack scenario, there's a
lot of really interesting
um things that you can put together with
like DOM clobbering or um some sort of
like page rewrite or on hover and all
sorts of you know, clickjacking even
like depending, you know, I know a lot
of projects will say clickjacking is out
of scope. I've seen plenty of empty uh
empty POCs that were really impactful
sometimes especially in the the scenario
that I think of is when you have a a um
a
provider that allows you to register
your own OAuth resource or whatever and
then they don't have click you know,
X-Frame or CSP on the actual page where
you approve an OAuth transaction or
whatever. And so then, you know, you can
clickjack that page with one click you
have account takeover.
Uh it's pretty freaking impactful.
Yeah. Yeah, absolutely. So, there's a
lot of really interesting things you can
do with that. I think, you know, try to
really think outside the With with each
of these, right? The the goal is to sort
of think outside the box and really um
change your perspective on how this
attack would work in a standard scenario
and try to apply it very specifically to
this scenario you're you're attacking
on. Like how how can I use this within
the context of this company um and the
flows of their workflow in their
application to to get the highest impact
here, right? If it's like OAuth for
example, like what you said. Like if you
can add an OAuth app and there's no um
X-Frame options and and and protective
headers on that specific approval page,
well, can you create an OAuth app that
could do full access to the account and
leverage that
to, you know, get a full account
takeover because that's like a really
creative way of using that application
to your advantage. I I I also kind of
think that that, you know, we kind of
mentioned this in the context of HTML
injection, but clickjacking is kind of
its own
like little gadget here. So, I'm going
to actually add that to its own own one
here because, you know, it really that
miss those missing frame headers give
you a lot of
flexibility when it comes to getting a
window reference. So, you can use that
to exploit post message attacks. You can
use that to for some cross-site leaks.
You can do a bunch of stuff with that.
Um
and uh of course, you know, the whole
iframing thing got a little bit tricky
when same-site default came into place
because it's like, okay, well,
unless the cookies are set to same-site
none, there's actually not going to be
cookies to that iframe when you do it.
Um but in some scenarios people are
still setting cookies to same-site none,
so it's definitely something to to keep
an eye on. Um the the thing that I
wanted to mention with with the HTML
injection piece was this
long screenshot that I put in the doc,
Joel, about
about DOM clobbering and how deep you
can go with DOM clobbering because like
a while back I did a I did a tweet about
like, hey, you know, we've got this
scenario. How do we How do we
get this attribute to be, you know, x.y
or whatever, right? And And essentially
I I was looking into that and I was
like, okay, there's some cool stuff you
can do with HTML injection and that sort
of thing. But man, you can go deep on
this thing. So, like you can control
attributes down to it seems like 1 2 3 4
at least the fifth layer and maybe
indefinitely using
nested iframes in the source doc
attribute. So, if you do like iframe
name equals A
and then iframe and then the source doc
for that is another iframe
and the source doc for that is another
iframe and the source doc for that is
another iframe with the name sort of all
the way down the line and then
eventually using either a form with an
input or an A A tag, then you can
actually like access you can DOM clobber
an attribute, you know, a.b.c.d.e
which is like way stronger than I
thought it was. Um yeah, absolutely. And
I've I've seen I've seen it recently
also exploited some somebody showed me
an exploit where they were able to DOM
clobber some script that was uh
potentially preventing them from getting
XSS on a specific target and I was like,
wow, this is a masterpiece. Well, and so
it's it's like one of those things
that's like um
you know, this is a perfect example of a
gadget, right? Where this type of
behavior, this like a.b.c. whatever
combined with like an HTML injection,
right? You see an HTML injection, you
your first thought is probably like,
okay, I can't really do anything with
that. Move on.
But if that's in the back of your head
and you're looking through your app and
you notice this weird thing in the JS
that's like referencing something from
the body in this format, well, now this
is a gadget, right? You can combine
these two things together. You can
elevate your impact. You can possibly
get XSS. You can probably, you know,
get, you know, a host of different
things depending on, you know, how it's
being used. And so, just having that in
your mind and understanding how it can
be used in different ways is so so
powerful.
Yeah. That That's
Go ahead.
What I was going to say is is
What I was going to
It's like when you're walking towards
somebody and you both go Exactly. You
just go in the same direction.
Um yeah,
what I was what I was going to say with
this as well is that we should I should
have said this before we got in, but the
term gadget is really important in in
this industry I think and and these are
essentially the the point of this is
that you should be taking note of all
these things. And whenever you see
something sketchy like this,
this is something that should make you
sort of feel like you're making progress
on hacking an application even though
you don't have an actionable
vulnerability. And I think
not only is this really important from a
technical perspective being able to
chain all of these together to achieve
an an actual impact in the application,
but it's also important from a
motivation perspective to to feel like,
hey, you know, maybe if I'm not finding
something, you know,
I'm feeling starting to feel really bad.
But
instead, you know, I can identify these
gadgets along the way and that can help
me make me
feel like I'm making progress hacking
this application even if I'm not getting
an actionable vulnerability. So, the the
goal of these, one, help you maintain
motivation. Two,
you know, make sure your spidey senses
are triggering and you're thinking
through all the possibilities of
utilizing these these. And then three,
they should be something that you take
notes for
and that you might be able to come back
to later and utilize in a different
chain as you discover additional
functionality.
So, that was what I was going to say. I
don't know. After that long rant, do you
remember what you were going to say? I I
do. I do. I do. So, what I was going to
say is the other aspect to HTML
injection especially more recently is
there is the CSS
injection aspect. CSS exfiltration.
There was a bunch of new research that
came out recently from PortSwigger
security and I think you could do all of
that with HTML injection, right?
Yeah, so
yes, I would actually consider CSS
injection a escalation of HTML
injection. Right. Right.
You know, would I put it in the same
category? I mean, technically XSS is is
you know, HTML injection in most
scenarios.
But yeah, I would actually kind of put
it in a different category and I don't
even know if we've got a gadget.
Man, we're just coming Joel, man, I I
need to We're coming up with gadgets. I
got two more here. D, really? Oh my
gosh. CSS injection.
Yes, so that Oh, yeah, at this point,
yeah. Yeah, CSS injection is getting
added to the list as well. Lots of great
stuff you can do with that. I consider
that to be an escalation of HTML
injection.
And and the the context in which I think
about HTML injection mostly is like a
scenario that you have a a
like
a
a sanitizer or something that you just
can't get around. Like Angular's, you
know, HTML sanitizer or whatever. And
you can only get some attributes in, but
um you can you can get in, you know, an
A tag or like something like that that
would allow you to to do uh DOM
clobbering or you could do, you know, an
image tag or something which we'll talk
about a little bit later cuz there's
some specific stuff you can do with
image tag. So, but yeah, CSS injection
as well. A lot of flexibility especially
with the new framework released by
PortSwigger research team.
Well, I do kind of love that perspective
as well, right? Like when we were
talking with Ben, he was like, oh yeah,
when I'm testing for XSS and stuff like
that, I'm always just putting like U
tag, H1 tag, some text. And it's
basically exactly what you said, right?
XSS is just an escalation of HTML
injection.
And it really depends on context,
depends on the, you know, whether or not
there's CORS, whether or not you have
CSP, like all sorts of different thing
aspects that are related to that
webpage, but it starts as an HTML
injection. And that's how, you know, a
lot of people like Ben and myself test
for XSS is just start with HTML
injection. Can I get an HTML tag in
here?
Then can I escalate that to CSS
injection? Can I escalate that to an
XSS? Can I escalate that to a DOM
clobbering? What can I escalate that to?
But it all starts sort of from that one
that one root point. Yeah, absolutely.
And And just taking a step back,
excuse me, taking a step back for a
second to HTML injection.
Um from our two tangents we did to
clickjacking and to CSS injection. Um
Another way to exploit this is dangling
markup attacks. And these are pretty
rare to be able to see it that
you know, uh
see it see it that have actual impact.
But the dangling markup attack is
essentially you leave
your tag open
and and or you leave your attribute open
and essentially you're able to include
some sensitive piece of information or
break the syntax on some important piece
of the client side code that allows you
to prevent something.
Great example of this is like state
page state. So a lot of times pages will
have a big JSON blob in a script tag at
the at the head of the page that has
like your whole page state or whatever
for these you know these single page
applications a lot of times.
And if you can inject that JSON object
and cause it to close the script tag, it
will leak the rest of that state object
into the HTML body which you can then
you know query and and and basically you
know it's like a cookie leak in some
some cases. It has a lot of different
impacts depending on what it is.
Huh. That that's pretty cool piece of
that. I hadn't I hadn't thought about
that one quite as much.
Yeah, the the traditional scenario I
kind of think of is if you're able to
like
actually do this in like an email or
something like that and you can leak the
the value or maybe leak a CSRF token or
that.
Both of those both of those would be
pretty cool. In that scenario.
of email actually cuz that's also HTML
injection.
What do you do you have any email
escalations cuz this is one that I I hit
pretty frequently and every time I see
it I'm like that's that's neat but I
have nothing like I you know what am I
going to you know maybe I can fish them
or something but
So the only scenario that I really
report HTML injection in email is if you
can literally overwrite the whole email.
And and the subject is like
something very
you know
Yeah, basically arbitrary email.
Generic. Yeah. It's
It's too I know it's earlier for you.
It's early for me man and my brain isn't
quite quite kicking into full gear yet.
But yeah, if you can overwrite literally
the whole email and the
the subject line is like important
information.
Yeah, you know or something like that.
Then it's like okay, well this is
actually pretty impactful. And
and so yeah, that that's one scenario
that I that I do report it. The the
other thing that comes to mind when I
think of dangling markup is sort of like
a stored
HTML injection on a victim. So let's say
for example you're you're able to like
send a notification to a victim's
account um that that gets displayed on
their home page, right? And then you can
do some sort of dangling markup attack
that DOSes the whole page. You know,
that that just breaks the whole flow of
the page and makes it impossible for
them to use the application. That the
impact there is is a lot stronger than
most anything else you could do from an
HTML injection perspective because of
the effect of the availability on the
application for the victim.
So that's that's another cool way you
can exploit HTML injection, I think.
Yeah, that's one of those good sort of
DOS use cases that is actually like
pretty solid especially where it's like
zero interaction.
You know, DOS can be very hit or miss
but I feel like zero interaction on
another user is one of the
the nice sort of cases that you can
Yeah, you can make a really good case
and say okay, I can pick any user and
they load the page up and it doesn't
work for them ever again. As a
non-technical user most people would get
stuck there. You know, a lot of people
don't you know clear cookies and
whatever is causing the issue. I mean
and if it's an XSS or HTML thing,
current cookie is going to do nothing.
So you know, it really depends on the
site and and how it works but you can
get a lot of impact out of DOS if you do
it right. Yeah, 100% So so we've covered
clickjacking, CSS injection, HTML
injection and
Excuse me, as as we mentioned along the
way, you know, all of these require an
extra piece, right? In the email you
you've got to be able to do the the
whole email and the the the subject line
has to be something and DOM clobbering
you've got to have like a crazy JS
scenario.
In the dangling markup you've got to be
able to leak some sensitive information
and in the in the dangling markup to DOS
you've got to be able to inject it
actually into the victim's it's got to
be stored, targeted dangling markup
injection essentially. Um
And when I thought about that attack
scenario, I think about one of my
favorite ones and I think I've talked
about this on the pod before but I'll
mention it again.
And this was an image injection, okay?
And this is not even like I wasn't
breaking out of any context. And we'll
kind of talk about context breaks a
little bit later as as a gadget in and
of themselves but
if you're able to inject into the source
attribute of an image, there's some
weird stuff you can do. And and
especially if you can do it in a
targeted way. For example, there was a
scenario much like the dangling markup
example that I I gave just a second ago
where I was able to do a stored image
injection on somebody essentially within
an application, okay? And I could force
the browser to load up a specific image.
And then what I did is I forced them to
hit the logout endpoint.
And with the image
Yeah. Yeah, so essentially I would send
them a message and then that message
would get pushed to their you know
dashboard or whatever. And that
dashboard would have an image. And then
as soon as they log into their
dashboard, it would load that image and
log them out. And then as soon as they
tried to do anything on the application,
it would get it would they'd get logged
out and then be forced to re-auth. And
then when they re-auth they would go
back to the dashboard page.
And
you know, and so there's there's a
couple ways that you can exploit this. I
actually exploited it again recently in
a scenario where
there wasn't a logout CSRF but there was
a login CSRF.
So so you can you could
essentially repeatedly log them into a
different account and then they could
never get access to their own account.
Okay. So it it's it's it's sort of a
tricky exploit for sure but image
injection and then I know there used to
be like like 401 injection or something
like that. I don't know if that works in
any browsers. We've kind of
We we keep on talking about that and
then we still don't know.
But I know so
at one point people were using 401
injection on an image in a image source.
And that would pop up a an auth box that
would allow you to exfiltrate auth
under a different sites domain. In fact,
our friend Mr. Sam Curry has a has a
disclosed report on Twitter from 2017.
Oh my gosh. Sam, what have you done?
Marked as a low. Marked as a low.
That
is exactly this HT HTTP 401 response
injection.
Hey guys, real quick I want to remind
you about the critical thinking Discord
community. There's been a ton of great
activity on the chats lately. People
just kind of shooting the breeze to drop
in new hacking tips and advice,
sharing cool research, that sort of
thing. So it's definitely something
you're going to want to get in on if you
haven't already. Also we've got the
subscriber tiers in place now which will
give you access to really cool things
like masterclass,
AMA,
just random scripts that I drop. It's
kind of like our inner circle. So if you
want to get in on that, please do. We
would really appreciate it. Also it
helps support the show. So if you're
interested in any of that, head over to
ctv.show/discord
to join the community today and we'll
see you over there. All right, back to
the show.
I don't know. There are some edge cases
in which this might work in mobile
browsers or in like Firefox or something
like that. So if you're really really
grasping for straws, you know, in a live
hacking event and you're like I got to
find something here, you know, then it
might be might be worth the report. It
might land you a low but
definitely the stuff with the targeted
image injection, I mean to be honest
that can get you into a high.
Because if you can literally just DOS
the whole app for a targeted user,
that's availability high. Yeah, I mean I
feel like that's that's impact right
there. If you can figure out some way to
to to demonstrate that then then there
you go, right?
So speaking of
desperateness and
you know, if you're really desperate
report this, open redirects. So let's
talk about open redirects cuz
from the program side I see this a lot
actually where people report open
redirects with no impact and
I
I could not recommend against it any any
stronger.
Like that.
Like I really I think open redirects are
like one of the lamest bug classes by
itself and like there really is like no
impact in today's day and age, right?
Like like just by itself like I can send
you to a link you go to another link. At
best fishing.
Like
it's it's a very very hard use case
exploitation case I find.
But what you can do with that, there are
a ton of things, right?
Couple great examples. SSRFs. A lot of
times they'll be either a filter on the
URL that's being that you're being sent
to or that's being requested to that
needs to be within a certain host name
or within a certain IP range.
You can use that as a redirect to go to
you know AWS metadata or something.
We we we've seen that you know that that
technique has been around forever and
stuff like that. So that that's
definitely a tried and true use case for
open redirects. The ones that I'm I'm
more interested in nowadays are the
OAuth path reversals essentially you
being able to
leak an OAuth token via
open redirect. And the the ones that I I
think are actually more
interesting are client side path
reversals and or iframe injections
essentially. Iframe source injections.
So you know, if you can if you can
provide a a place where you're supposed
to be able to embed any page on
on a specific website in an application
then you can use an
an open redirect in that in that
environment to get your own page
embedded in there. That's that's a
scenario that once again is a gadget
that can that can
expose a lot of um
helpful things like post message
listeners.
You know, in
in mobile's case, you know, sometimes
you can get use it for like like
JavaScript what are they called?
JavaScript bridges or something like
that, Joe? Yep. Yep. Yep. JavaScript
interfaces.
Yeah, so just you know, accessing
specific
functions or or um parameters on the
window object to interact with the
actual application. Um, really cool
purposes there. And dude, this is the
one that just like lately has been
just so so cool to see work. We talk
about client-side path reversals all the
time, and client-side path reversals are
kind of a gadget of themselves. Um, but
this is a great example where you can
put two gadgets together to make a ball,
right? So, let's say you've got a
client-side path reversal.
So, essentially what what that means is
you're able to control um either the the
the place to which a fetch request is
sent or like maybe even an iframe that's
embedded dynamically using JavaScript or
something like that. Um
Uh but normally the fetch scenario is is
where it's at. And you're able to inject
into that URL scheme and traverse and
then hit an open redirect. So, I saw
somebody at the live hacking event do
this.
going to say. Yeah, and and I also my
mentee sitting right there at that at
that desk behind me found one the other
day and fully exploited it. And I was
just like
Nice. dude, this bug is like
so clutch. Yeah.
Um
and so I really love to see it used with
the client-side path reversal where you
traverse, hit the open redirect, fetch
automatically follows redirects, um
which I don't know. I won't go down the
path of of winding about that bug that I
found recently where I I couldn't
actually exploit it because fetch auto
follows redirects and you can't even
read the redirect location ever.
Uh But uh but seeing that actually work
out in a client-side path reversal
environment is amazing, and it so often
works out to be XSS even in like heavily
sanitized environments because they're
not expecting malicious input to come
back from a fetch request that they sent
to their own API, right?
Right. So, there's pretty much no way to
to you know, properly anticipate that.
Um, so that's a really cool use case for
an open redirect. Yeah, I mean there's
so much protection and advice on the
server side with SRF, right? Where it's
like, "Okay, never take a user control
parameter and and make a request to it."
And all this stuff. But then like so
much of that
falls to the wayside on the client side
because it's just not the same thought
process and there's so much different
development around like, you know, it
seems very harmless, right? You're like,
just getting a query parameter or
something. And but that that's all it
takes, you know, that that's you just
putting it in a fetch request and
because of that behavior and the
ubiquity of Um
you know, open redirects and all that
kind of stuff. It just makes it such a
larger
problem. And with all these single page
applications nowadays, it's you know,
even more so, right? Um
So, so yeah, really really interesting
stuff there. Yeah, I So
I don't know about what you said about
the open redirect. I think open redirect
is right on the line of like if a
company is really taking security
seriously, they want to clean that up
because it can be used in so many
scenarios, right? Um But don't be
surprised if it's a low, you know, you
know, at like at face value, you know
what I mean? If you report it, like
they're just going to be like, "Okay, I
guess we'll fix this." But like
minimum value for sure. Yeah. Um and in
that scenario,
do really rarely you report that because
it's it's uh
much more high value to be able to use
it in a chain even if it's not present
rather than
Excuse me, man. Water this morning. Um
rather than chaining it into something
that's, you know, much higher value uh
down the line.
Yeah. So
will say I think at probably every
single live hacking event, at least once
I see in the collab channel somebody go,
"Hey, does anybody have an open redirect
on the site?"
open redirect, yeah. And you're like,
"Okay, yeah, this is still a thing. This
is still kicking." So,
check that out.
what's interesting about that, too, is
for all the people there that don't need
an open redirect but might have an open
redirect, like that should be
inspiration for you, right? Because
somebody needs an open redirect. Which
means that the open redirect that you
have,
somewhere there is a use case for that,
you know? And you just got to go find
it. And the fact that that happens every
single live hacking event really sort of
lends itself to the scenario of like,
"Oh, I have an open redirect, but I
can't really find anything to do with
it." Well, that's definitely out there,
you know? Somebody's There's definitely
some place that it opens up. Exactly.
Exactly. Exactly. So, that should be
inspiration for any of you that
either need an open redirect or or don't
need an open redirect and should need an
open redirect. Um Yeah, absolutely. Uh
so sort of tangential gadget to that is
the client-side open redirect. And this
one I actually think is garbage.
Um
and I actually was
There's a pretty serious differentiation
between client-side redirect open
redirect and uh server-side open
redirect, right? Um
Depending on the scenario, you know, you
still may be able to use it. The pretty
much the only use I could come up with
is iframe uh
iframe source injection, essentially.
Like there's pretty much nothing else
you can really do with it. If you're
doing like a window.location.href and
you cannot do the JavaScript scheme,
then you're
I mean you're you're pretty much
screwed. It doesn't It doesn't leak the
hash. It doesn't leak any of the query
parameters. It just goes to the location
that you define with the input that you
inputted. Um and so I don't know, maybe
I'm missing something there, and I'd be
interested if anyone in the community
can point me in the direction of
something that I might be able to do
with this besides, you know, injecting
into an iframe, but that's pretty much
the only thing I could come up with.
Yeah, I'm trying to think if there's
anything creative. Probably the best
scenario I can come up with is like
maybe on mobile, depending on the
permissions within a web view, you could
redirect to a file or something like
that. Um and then, you know, pivot from
there depending on But but that's going
to be very situation specific. Um
Yeah. So, yeah, I mean it's one of those
things that as a again as a gadget, like
it potentially has use cases, but
they're very very narrow, especially
even for the ones that we've been
talking about like client-side open
redirects is
really like
you know, one in a hundred type barely
barely ever use, but but it's there and
have it in the back of your mind. You
know what is not not a vulnerability
but
and is not really even a gadget but kind
of feels like one is uh postMessage open
redirect. Yeah.
I've kind of run into this scenario a
lot where it's like, "Okay, I'm really
close to XSS because if I could just you
send this postMessage to redirect the
page to a JavaScript URI, then I'd have
XSS, but you can't use the JavaScript
URI because of some, you know, very
tough to bypass sanitization or
something. But you can redirect the URL
to an arbitrary host."
Yeah. But it's it's useless because
essentially you unless it's in an
iframe, I guess is the only scenario
that that would actually be useful. And
then you could say like you know,
window.open X is is the new window,
right? And then dot frames one and then
send the postMessage to that or whatever
and have it redirect inside the trusted
page. Then it's a little bit useful. But
Um you can always just redirect the
other tab that you've opened up anyway
with window.open. So, you just do, you
know, X equals window.open and then
X.location equals XYZ and then you've
redirected the page to that location.
the windows, yeah. Yeah, exactly. And so
um
that didn't make the list this time
around on the on the gadget side but is
an honorable mention and also something
that I would kind of be interested to
see if anyone like knows any way that
that could be helpful. Maybe the only
thing that I could think of is like
uh it could maybe be helpful in like a
same-site strict scenario, right? Where
like you can't even do top-level
navigations to send the cookies. You've
got to actually come from a specific
origin. And if you could trigger the
redirect from
that origin, then you could trigger
get-based CSRF on a same-site strict
scenario.
Yeah, I mean and again,
right? It's like one of those really
like stretch scenarios that's going to
be super
Yeah, I don't know. I'm trying to think
if there's anything and I keep falling
back to like these more like native
scenarios where like an electron app or
like something that has more schemes or
like stuff that, you know, you all stuff
other than JavaScript and other than
HTML or sorry, HTTP or HTTPS
that maybe you could you could exploit
in some creative way, but uh
yeah, I don't know. It's It's very very
tricky. Mm. It is. It is. Yeah.
I don't know, man. We'll see. We'll see
if any anybody in the community comes up
with something. I've got like 10 of them
in my
You know, actually interesting
interesting point. I didn't even put it
on this list cuz I haven't figured out a
way to use it ever, but I do have it in
my notes, you know? Like it is something
that I keep in my notes.
Um so, maybe it's worth writing down,
you know, just in case just to Yeah,
like you never know. Like so there there
there definitely could be some browser
feature in the future that that makes it
really like a better exploitation
scenario. I think that happens in both
directions where there's new features or
like old features that get, you know,
sort of sunset and new features that get
rolled in that change how existing
you know, functionality within HTML and
JavaScript and all that kind of stuff
works.
And so potentially, you know, maybe who
knows
Yeah, within five years I'm writing this
in my report. In the next five years
Google could implement a new
vulnerability that allows me to exploit
this
critical
It'd be really I know that Gareth Hayes
sort of monitors the intent to ship
stuff for CSS because that's his, you
know, thing. Uh it it would be
interesting to like have a feed of
information that about things that
Google
Google Chrome or Chromium intends to
ship that could have security impact
just to kind of be keeping your eye out
for the ways that that could be
exploited in the near future when they
actually do ship that. That that's an
interesting Somebody make a Twitter bot
for that, please. That'd be That'd be
really cool to follow.
Um All right, next one on the list is
leaking window.location.href
and this can be done
multiple ways. Uh it could The most
common one that we we saw um and we know
from the um
Franz Rosen Dirty Dancing write-up is uh
via post message essentially. If there's
a scenario where
you send a message to the client and it
sends back, you know, the
the URL uh
that that the current page is on. Uh
this is a very helpful gadget for
leaking
uh
IDs, OAuth tokens, you know, pretty much
anything you can name uh that that ends
up in the URL, the hash, that sort of
thing. Um lots of lots of cool
applications there if you can combine it
with another another uh
you know, gadget of sorts.
Yeah. Yeah, absolutely. I mean, um
there's so many
various like ways to escalate post
message bugs. Um
and it's just one of those things that
like if you're not looking for post
message as a whole, like
you may install Chrome uh from Franz's
Chrome uh
post message extension and just take a
look at all the communications that are
going between iframes and and and window
frames and all that kind of stuff
because there is so much behind the
scenes stuff that's going on in like
every single website um that is really
really interesting and it's definitely
worth taking a look at cuz a lot of that
behavior is not gated properly and it's
doing all sorts of really funky things
including, you know, leaking
window.location.href and
way worse, you know, like yeah. I mean,
I think we've both seen some really
insane scenarios of of, you know, just
like sending local storage back or, you
know, all all all sorts of crazy things.
Yeah. Yeah,
post message stuff is super interesting
and actually I'm kind of I was trying to
think about what
other ways that there could be to leak
the window.location.href.
And I'm I'm wondering,
you know, there could be some weird
scenario where like you could provide a
host and then it would redirect to that
host with the current path or something
like that.
And then you could leak the path
which is the path in the in the hash in
the query parameters which is the more
sensitive part, not the actual domain.
Um
and I'm actually also looking right now.
I actually have not done a lot of stuff
with window.name
and I'm a little bit fuzzy on how it
works still.
Um so I'm wondering if it would be
possible for us to go ahead and do a
window.name
like open a new tab, have that tab set
window.name, right? And then
redirect that tab away using the same
thing we talked about earlier how you
can just do, you know, x equals
window.open, x.location. And then can I
check j.name here? Yeah, I can. So if
they if they update window.name with
anything, then you can you can
then
retransfer the the uh
you know, domain, the origin, the
current location.href back to a domain
that you control and then you can read
window.name
which may have some sensitive
information in it. So that's an
interesting uh an interesting vector as
well to leak some information cross
origin.
Yeah, absolutely. And, you know,
um as we talked about, you can there's a
lot of like cross
uh it as long as you're behaving within
like same origin and whatever like
headers and stuff are being set, um you
know, you can reference windows by the
same name uh without like changing them.
Um and even within that window like
within if you open a tab or a window
with a name, that window has its own
name reference that it can it can call
back to.
Um so there's there's definitely some
really weird stuff. We were talking
about this in the episode that'll come
out uh before this one um with with
Youssef um Samuda about, you know, sort
of a lot of the intricacies of of
window.open and window.opener and parent
and and all these these these sort of
weird
Yeah, it's it's very very There's so
many facets and I'm still super curious
about how this stuff is working behind
the scenes, like how the browser is
determining that kind of stuff like when
it opens it and when it tracks it and
what where when it understands like user
interaction
to certain things like a user has to
click something to pop an XSS. Like how
does it Like how is it how is the
browser tracking that state? Um so there
there's I think a lot of really
interesting research that could be done
there, but uh I won't get too too in the
weeds on that.
So I was
as as we do, I was looking at
the browser object or the window object
that gets returned from a window.open um
thing the other day and, you know,
there's frames, there's location,
opener, parent, post message, you know,
top, all of these things that we are
kind of familiar with. And then there's
a couple that I wasn't really expecting
to find here, which is focus and blur.
Um and those are functions that you can
call on the window and uh focus will
allow you to focus that specific tab.
I'm not sure what blur does. I didn't
assess that one. Close obviously will
close that tab. But I do wonder if
there's anything that you can trigger
on like via cross origin via calling
that focus function.
Um
and whether you can do sort of like a
pop under of sorts with that.
It's kind of a little bit little bit
tricky. Uh but it seems like you can
force essentially the user to focus on
that other frame from the other side
from the opener frame even if you
they've clicked back to the opener frame
which is a little bit a little bit
tricky because I feel like that's
something that should be a user land
decision, you know?
Yes, indeed. And you're correct that
like basically if you have like another
window that's been opened and you have a
reference to it and you have that window
like elsewhere on your monitors or like,
you know, you're clicked into a
different window and you do win.focus,
it will focus your
context basically over to that that
other window. It'll it'll change your
window like that you're actively on over
to the target one.
Interesting.
I wonder
And I assume blur does the same. It's
really hard to test it because
You can't really be on the same tab.
Yeah, you'd have to do like a timeout or
something.
Set timeout.
Huh. Well, I'm sorry. I I knew I just
knew you sniped us in the middle of an
episode. Um
interesting stuff there. I wonder if
anybody in the community is aware of any
attack vectors that um sort of
originate from window.focus or
window.blur and if there might be any
way for us to trigger on event handlers
or something like that in the other
window
via those functions in a cross origin
scenario. Um
so definitely definitely really cool
stuff there. I was trying to like
essentially go through that whole object
to see if there's anything, you know,
different in self or top or window or
anything like that that I hadn't seen
before, but besides those two, blur and
focus, I I think it's been all pretty
pretty well documented. Um Yeah, I I
think I'll have to read it read into
what the actual docs are doing cuz I I
did do a like while you while you nerds
knighted me here, I did a little test
here where I basically I focused it and
then I did like a 2-second timeout and
then I blurred the same window and
nothing like it focused it when I did
focus, but then when I did blur, nothing
happened um from that same window. So
here. I I wonder what the actual use
case of those are. It's kind of Yeah,
I'm sure it's in the docs somewhere, but
yeah. Cool. Um okay, so
actually I I got another one. This one's
a really interesting one and I I want to
say thanks to Matan Behar for actually
pointing this one out because I tweeted
out that I was prepping this episode and
he's like, "Hey, I got some gadgets that
you probably didn't think of." And I was
like, "Oh, really? Oh, really? Come at
me, bro." And he's like, "Okay."
And so he sent me one and lo and behold,
I forgot one that he he had. I had um
all the other ones. He sent me five. Um
and one of them I sort of sort of had,
so I'll give him a half point for that.
So
um still pretty impressive because
the guy's 16 years old and is stumping
me on a regular basis when it comes to
client-side stuff. So
pretty crazy dude, but the one that he
came up with that I kind of forgot about
was one that I've talked about on the
podcast many many times, which is a
cookie refresh gadget. Um and
essentially the scenario where this is
useful is when you're trying to exploit
top-level Let me see if I can get all of
the all of the adjectives of this
scenario. Same site lacks default
top-level post-based
CSRFs.
Um if you when you're trying
lacks
Same site lacks default
top-level navigation, top-level nav
Yeah.
post-based
CSRFs.
Okay. Yeah, I just kind of I kind of
rattled it off there. Um but and the
reason why this is is um
uh interesting, of course, is because of
the two 2-minute lacks uh same site
lacks default uh sort of caveat that
they've put into place um for
Just disappearing, right? Yes, be I
don't know. I have They keep on saying
it's disappearing, but I haven't seen it
anytime. Um but uh when when it
disappears, it's going to be a sad day
cuz that's going to be the nail in the
coffin for CSRF, man. Um but essentially
this is a 2-minute period after cookie
is set that they it will actually send
that cookie in cross origin top-level
post message or not post message, excuse
me, post HTTP requests. They're Those
are very confusing between those two um
even though they're not similar at all.
Um
and that that can result in CSRF. So if
you have a gadget that will reset
refresh your session cookie, then that
will allow you to reset that timer and
increase the efficacy and and
consistency of of CSRF exploit um
and and access essentially make it a
better report. So, that is another thing
to keep in your pocket and it's unlikely
something that the the companies will
fix as well. So, if you find it, you
kind of got it in your pocket for
you know, any post-based CSRFs that will
happen in the future for that company.
Yeah, super interesting and you got me
on a rabbit hole again where I was
looking for this
in the in the Google Chromium release
notes
about the same site updates the same
site and
and this update back in 2019 with the
lax plus post stuff
giving basically the 2-minute window
that we're talking about, but I I am not
seeing anything that's really
where they're going to phase it out?
Yeah, I mean there are have been updates
you know, in 2021 which is still I guess
3 years old now, but
there's been nothing really new there
that I can see
about sort of the time limit on that
being changed. So,
maybe we're still in luck. I I there's
tweets you know, that are 3-plus years
old that are
you know, going back to when this first
came out that are like CSRF is 120
seconds. So, there's a there's a lot of
you know, clarity this has been a thing
for a while.
I think this is also something that
programs don't really understand fully
at this point
because I haven't ever had anyone give
me kickback on like hey, well this only
works for the first 120 seconds of the
session being live. Um, so I I wonder
whether you know, there's been a little
bit of a scenario of like hackers kind
of pull in a fast one on programs and
submitting an exploit that only works
for 120 seconds. Um, and
them just not knowing any better.
Because when you when you reproduce a
vulnerability, you log into your account
right before you start you know, the the
the reproducing of it and so you're
within that 2-minute frame and then you
got to and if it doesn't work, what do
you do? You log out, you log back in and
you try it again.
It and so it's a little bit it's a
little bit something that the program
side should be aware of because
I think it actually does affect whether
or not this exploit is actually going to
affect users in at the end of the day.
Yeah, for sure for sure.
Cool. Let's talk about
let's talk about stored XSS. Let's keep
let's go back to like basics, you know.
Um,
stored XSS.
One really common pitfall I see with
this is self stored XSS.
And self stored XSS is not not
necessarily like immediately just non
non-issue.
Um, I think there are still a lot of
interesting scenarios, but the key is
exploitation.
So, like is there a CSRF that you can do
to update your profile to create that
self stored XSS which you can then pop
somewhere else. Um, you know, I think
that there are stored XSS is not
necessarily always like as clean cut and
straightforward as it seems,
but it is a great way to force
you know, user interaction basically
where
you know,
either through CSRF or clicking a button
or HTML injection or
there's sort of a lot of different
aspects to this that you can you can
take advantage of.
The the forced user interaction piece is
interesting because it's like okay,
I don't know. In my in my brain there's
three levels of user interaction. There
is no user interaction. Think of that
this here like you know, I doer that I
you just do something evil to my
account. Then there's partial user
interaction which is like okay,
there's user interaction, but we're not
really coming to the attacker's website
and we're doing stuff that we normally
do anyway.
Right?
Yeah, like clicking a link and it pops
an XSS.
Yeah, in your own in an application that
you trust and use on a regular basis.
And and then I think that is very very
close to no user user interaction
required. Like I would say that is you
know, 90%
the way to no no user interaction
required. And then obviously there's
user interaction required. So, if you
have a stored XSS, I think it's it's
helpful to think about it as a gadget in
some scenarios because you may be able
to use this. And then the other scenario
that I was I was kind of thinking about
this is like okay, you've got the stored
XSS.
Can you use an I doer to worm that
stored XSS everywhere and then turn that
you know, kind of that I doer into a
ATO and then essentially an arbitrary
account takeover on every single target.
And I think that's a pretty pretty
impactful scenario and one of the
easiest ways to get
arbitrary account takeover because
arbitrary account takeover is a tricky a
tricky bug
and this is one of the ways that I think
it actually counts as arbitrary account
takeover.
Yeah, and especially if you have those
the right gadgets in place. Like if you
have a CSRF and a stored XSS, that
wormable capability is really like
depending on what your CSRF is.
Uh, so say you have a CSRF to update
profile
and and a stored XSS. Well, huge
wormable potential because your worm can
pop a CSRF that updates your somebody
else's profile to create the worm that
right and so it just keeps going.
And so you know, depending on the right
gadgets again, right? Depending on what
you have you can really do a lot of
stuff.
Yeah. Plus a stored XSS.
Yeah. Stored self XSS. I mean, Yeah, I
mean that's pretty much how you yeah,
okay. I see what you're saying. I see
what you're saying. Yeah, that that that
is an interesting combination there cuz
you can then then force it to store it
on their own
you know, profile or whatever. Okay.
Right. Yeah, I would almost consider
that
Yeah, I'd almost consider that just a a
stored XSS cuz well, no because then
stored XSS can also originate from
others. Yeah, that that is sort of an
edge case scenario that I hadn't really
thought about very much is like Where do
you draw the line on like wormable? Like
what what makes it wormable for you?
Yeah,
I guess wormable for me is kind of like
okay,
it's almost going back to that same
thing that I was saying before with like
no user interaction or you know, minimal
user interaction
required where you're just going about
the application yourself. Something pops
and then now you're the one spreading
the
the payload,
so I could definitely see that in that
scenario. And by nature of stored XSS or
or XSSs in general,
there's a decent amount of
wormability because of how much control
you have over the user session.
And so that you know, I wonder how many
XSS scenarios
I haven't really fleshed out from a
threat modeling perspective because I
wasn't firmly portraying the risk that
comes along with wormability in some of
these because if you can then force the
victim to host their their you know,
send that XSS to all of their friends or
whatever or all of their connections in
whatever application then I think
there's a lot of there's a lot of impact
there. That's yeah. Wormability I think
a lot of times XSS sort of gets gets
automatically turned into like ATO or
like trying to get ATO or something like
that.
But it doesn't necessarily have to be
that to get impact. Like if you can't
find a good way to do an attack an
account takeover, well maybe you can
still have a CSRF that lets you worm the
XSS and that's still plenty of impact
I'd say.
You know, at least maybe from like a DOS
perspective or who know like I there's a
lot of different angles you can take.
Even just the worming itself might be
enough. So,
I
the CSRF so I I think I understand what
you're saying from this from CSRF, but
it strikes me a little bit wrong because
it's not cross-site anymore if you've
triggered a stored XSS, right? What
you're talking about is writing an
exploit with the CSRF.
CSRF request forgery. Yeah,
it's like it's XSS exploitation, you
know, where it's like you you use your
JavaScript context and the ability to
control the user's session in that in
that user's browser to trigger
XSS in other scenar- I mean if it's
already yeah, exactly.
You use that position to force XSS on
other trigger different actions on the
site or force XSS on other users, right?
Right. Like I think like in a perfect
scenario like you find an XSS and
there's no
you know, other way to worm this or you
can't really do anything the XSS is an
XSS and that's going to lower the impact
a lot, but if you know, you're going
through sort of your different
exploitation scenarios and you can find
some way to propagate that XSS onto
other people then you know, through you
know, I I'll agree like it's not really
cross-site, but like kind of same site
like request forgery like cross-page
request forgery whatever however you
want to, but you know, at its core you
know, being able to you know, call call
other endpoints and stuff from that XSS.
Potentially there that's a really good
exploitation scenario you can you can
approach. Yeah, 100%. I I definitely see
that. And and I also think XSS is just
kind of
underrated as a
vulnerability type
whereas ATO is kind of glorified because
it's like okay, now I can exfiltrate the
session and now I can log into the
victim's account on my computer.
Great. You know, like I could just do I
also could just write a script to do
whatever I wanted to do in that victim's
browser and then just be done. And
actually it's more likely that I'll do
that because if if I'm a mass exploiting
this, I'm not going to get okay, you
know, Joe's session just popped in like
let's just log in and like see what he
you know, has or whatever. It it it's
going to be like no, I'm going to uh,
you know, write a script to transfer all
your money to me, you know, and then
from your
from your browser, you know,
so there's no trace. And and so um,
yeah, I I think ATO is a little over
glorified in those scenarios, but I also
understand the impact of like yeah,
well, now I have persistent access to
the victim's session.
Um, all right. So, the other one another
one that I have on the list here which
is a which is a vuln in and of itself so
is stored XSS and so some of the other
things we've mentioned is CRLF
injection. And whoo, CRLF injection is
powerful man because you can really do a
lot of stuff with controlling
uh,
like response headers and cookies and
all sorts of stuff like that. I I you
know, a CRLF injection I I a lot of
people don't think about this. A CRLF
injection is more powerful than a
reflected XSS in the scenarios where you
can, you know, trigger the reflected XSS
from the CRLF injection. The only
scenario where that isn't the case, um,
normally is on a 302 redirect or like a
300 status code redirect. Um, but
normally, you know, if you've got a a
solid clean CRLF injection, that is a,
you know, you have a lot of capabilities
there. Um,
Yeah, I mean, it's basically full
response control.
Yeah. Yeah, and uh, that that is very
powerful. So, definitely something, you
know, I
whether or not this one kind of gets put
on the list or not, and because it is
its own vulnerability was kind of iffy,
but there's definitely, um, some
capabilities of things you can do with
setting setting cookies, um,
HTTP only cookies, or um,
like headers, uh,
controlling
the aspect of the header. For example,
one of the reasons, reason I'm a little
bit salty about this right now is the
other day I was like, ah, you know, I
really need this
I really need a way to leak the
redirect. I I I said I wasn't going to
talk about it. I'm I'm going to talk
about it. It's
It's annoying, man. It's really
So, there's a scenario where I needed to
I had an XSS and I needed to leak the
response of a, uh, fetch request to an
arbitrary location
or to a location and, uh, that location
would have a token in the response, but
it was a 302. And it would then
instantly consume the token on the next
page.
And all of the access control headers
were there,
you know, all all of that that [__] was
there, um, and I
like, but I still couldn't read it
because it it the browser automatically
follows the redirect at like the browser
level. It doesn't do it at like the
fetch level. And there is some some
stuff in fetch where you can say like,
"Hey, don't automatically follow the
redirect." And it's like, "Okay." But
then it gives you an opaque redirect
response where you can't read the
response even if the access control
headers
So, this cat is right in front of me
right now.
in my face.
god, dude, lovely. Um, anyway, I was
like, "Okay." I was talking to some
people and some people were like, "Hey,
why don't you, since you've got an XSS,
why don't you write a CSP that blocks
the the redirect?" Um, cuz it was on a
different origin, uh, when it goes to
consume the token. And I was like, ah,
that's a great idea. Um, but then it
triggers a 400 error and you can't read
the response. So, I was like, "Shit, how
do I leak that?" And I And I was
thinking, "Okay, well, maybe I can use
CSP reporting
to, uh,
send myself a report of that token and
leak the token." And unfortunately, you
can't because you're not allowed to
actually do this on the client side. Uh,
you can't set a report URI, uh, for a
a CSP on the client side. Um, but if I
had had a CRLF injection and that was
the origin of my XSS, then I could have
set the CSP in the header and set the
redirect the report URI and then trigger
this whole thing and then leaked the
token to my server via the the CSP
violation report. Um, which would have
been an absolute monster of a
vulnerability. That would have just been
Yeah. crazy. Um, but anyway, that's why
I'm a little bit like, oh, you know,
CRLF
a creative attack scenario. I've always
wondered about that like CSP reporting
URL thing and like what I don't even
know what data gets sent over there,
but, um, it's always seemed so Oh my
god, Zora's sitting on my delete key and
he's just
That's hilarious, dude.
He He just deleted our whole doc, dude.
He started deleting line by line. All
right, well, that's the end of this
episode. Um,
uh, thank goodness for control Z. All
right, dude, we've still got
We've got like at least six left and
we're
an hour left.
You You've got a hard stop when?
Uh,
30 minutes. Okay. All right, now, we're
good. We're good. All right, let's keep
let's keep plugging away. Um,
Okay.
So,
this is
I don't know whether we want to consider
this a gadget or not, but it's I'm I'm
calling this a place to stand, okay?
And I can kind of consider this a
gadget, uh, especially in So, there's
two ways this can be interpreted. One is
like a window reference in the client
side scenario. That's not what I'm
talking about.
I'm talking about a place to stand being
a reference to a certain object,
particularly in a GraphQL scenario. So,
like
essentially, when you're attacking
GraphQL APIs,
you need Sometimes you need a way to
reference an object from a specific
context. And I think having
thought through a
plausible scenario in the application's
threat model
from which a attacker, either in an
unauthenticated context or a lower
privileged context, can access a certain
piece of information or a certain object
um, in a GraphQL
sort of scheme
is a very important gadget, uh, because
you you can use that that
place to stand, that that reference, to
pull out various fields. Excuse me, uh,
fields about that object.
And I think that is really important and
something that is worth taking note of
because it's like, "Okay, I go through
this object, this object, this object,
this object, this object, and then I can
get access to the user object or
whatever." All right? And I think a lot
of times that that is a a useful piece
to keep on considering as you're
building out a your GraphQL schema on a
on a on a target that doesn't have
introspection enabled.
Yeah, and so, you know, on that topic,
we've talked about this a couple times,
I think, but couple tools that are
really useful. Clairvoyance is a big
one,
um, and especially for non-schema, and
uh, GraphQL,
what's it called? Uh, explorer play
playground?
Voyager or something like that?
Voyager, that's what it is. Yeah, so, it
Voyager gives you a graph, right? Is
that the
one we're Yeah. Yeah, Voyager gives you
basically a visual like graph view of
each object type, you know, within the
GraphQL schema and how different queries
and mutations, what objects they read
and how they connect to each other. And
it's just like what you're talking
about. Like, I think that was a perfect,
um, way to sort of illustrate the how
Voyager and that that attack scenario,
especially within GraphQL, can play
together where you have one object that
references another object, that queries
another object, and somewhere down the
line there's an access control that's
missing where it's, you know, calling
the same query or it's accessing an
object, um, that, you know, normally you
wouldn't have direct access to, but you
can get access to it another way. Um,
and that is super super useful to
understand sort of those relationships
within the GraphQL schema in order to to
find those things. Yeah, and I and I In
some scenarios, there are GraphQL setups
where it's like you will
they'll have like essentially a clone of
an object where it's like, it's not the
user, it's like
the external user or something like
that. And it
references the same database table or
row, clearly, but the fields are less
accessible. So, if you can figure out a
way to not access external user, but
access user, then you're really in good
shape. Um,
and you'd be able to leak a lot of
information. So, that sort of thing is
really interesting and something I'd
like to see a little bit more
development around in the community.
Yeah, the other thing on that, um, on
the ID oracle side is, you know, um,
UUIDs. This is a really big place where
this comes in as well. A lot of
companies use use UUIDs as a, uh,
protection mechanism against IDORs. And
they'll say, "Oh, we're using UUIDs, so
you can't predict, uh, you know, it's
not iter You can't enumerate on IDs. So,
if you have an IDOR, you have to have
some way to leak it, otherwise the
impact is significantly mitigated."
Fair. Uh, but ID oracle is perfect for
that. So, as as as a a gadget, right? If
you find some way, uh, to get from one
piece of
significantly easier accessible
information, email, phone number, user
ID, anything like that, to a UUID, oh
man, gold mine, right? Like, hold onto
that. That's a really big one. That's a
huge gadget. If you find something like
that, keep that in your notes because,
um, you know, later down the line you're
going to find some endpoint that's
relying on that behavior, that UUID
behavior, implicitly as a security
mechanism, and that's where you're going
to be able to really take advantage of
it. And you can probably reference it in
a bunch of other reports, too. So, Yeah.
Maybe find some other IDORs, too, and
and and go go ham, you know. Yeah, ID
oracle is is really big thing, whether
you're in a GraphQL environment or not.
And they're particularly They're easier
to find, I think, in a in a GraphQL
environment because of the, you know,
implicit relationships between various
objects and stuff like that. Um, so,
definitely ID oracle is another top-tier
gadget if you can get your hands on it.
Um,
Yeah, absolutely. the Oh, actually, see,
look at that.
I have I I did have clickjacking
reference in here. So, we can skip this
one. So, that's great. Um, the one of
the other ones that I want I wanted to
mention was an off gadget, okay? And
this one's kind of interesting. I've
sort of alluded to this on the podcast
before, but I haven't really, um, given
a name to it or anything. Um, but
essentially, what this is is a way for
you to move PR to N in scenarios where
where, uh,
you're normally dealing with PRL. And
some some programs will set
self-register accounts to PRL. That's
just how it is. Um, on HackerOne they're
not supposed to, but They're not
supposed to. The the the the published
program guidelines say that, uh, if
self-sign up is enabled, it should be
private for partner now. Exactly. And
but some programs will be like, "Hey,
you know, we've got to go You've got to
like provide a credit card validation or
something like that." And it's PRL or
like, "You got to validate your email."
So, it's PRL.
Which I can understand, right? Like,
especially for stuff like that, it's
like, "Okay, it is there it's not just
like random Joe Schmo unauthorized
attacker is
Exactly. able to exploit this. Right.
And And so, uh,
definitely in those scenarios, looking
for an off gadget is a really good way
to increase the impact of your reports
Because essentially what these off
gadgets do are they allow you to act as
an authenticated user for a specific set
of operations or
maybe you're like in you're like a guest
in a checkout flow. Like one of the
scenarios that I've seen this before is
like, you know, normally they try to
force you to like sign up for an account
when you
are trying to check out. But
in this scenario, you can there's like a
little button down at the corner you can
say like check out as guest or whatever.
And then it gives you a
off token
that's like guest 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 10
or whatever.
And then you can use that off token to
query things that aren't necessarily
related to checkout or anything like
that. And that would allow you to move
some of your vulnerabilities from PRL.
Let's say you have an IDOR in the
authenticated scope. Move that that from
PRL to PRN and that is going to give
your your volume a massive boost.
So keep an eye out for these things as
well. Have definitely landed me a couple
thousand dollars in escalations.
Yeah. Yeah, and this is kind of related
to that. But I would love to see more
research on like those auto login
behaviors that I see where like either
it's like an email gets sent to your or
a link gets sent to your email and you
just click it and you're auto logged in
or you know, stuff like that where that
is also kind of like like a zero to a
hundred type of off where you're going
from like nothing to like full account
login with basically no verification
other than like I have this email. Yeah.
Um and I think there's some really
interesting research that could happen
around that.
Especially like an off gadget
perspective where it's like, you know,
moving moving into sort of an
authenticated state without like logging
in so to speak.
And maybe there's some some interesting
stuff that you could do there. Because
there's so much information in this
industry
I'll restate this point because I think
I think a lot of people have heard of it
but you know, it may not be in the in
the forefront of your mind. This can
also be a really helpful thing the thing
you mentioned Joel login with a link or
whatever. Can be a really helpful thing
for bypassing your account getting
banned which happens a lot in in our
environment, right? Is like okay, you
try to log in it's like hey, your
account's banned.
And then you're like okay, well, I can't
really do any testing.
Do a password reset on that [__] and and
try to and reset your password and often
times they'll just dump you right into
the account. So I had that scenario the
other day where I was locked out of
account.
Everyone was also experiencing this
issue and then you do a password reset
and now you're in the app.
And it's a pain in the ass cuz every
single time you got to go to your email
and you got to answer whatever questions
and paste in the thing and reset your
password. How many you know,
extra characters do I have at the end of
my password? Who knows? Yeah. Um
but
that is another way to get access to
accounts that you may have been locked
out of. Um
yeah, so I guess let's see how many 1 2
3 Okay, let's let's do
let's do this this is an interesting
one. Once again, I got to shout out my
boy Matumb Bear.
The guy rocks and he is amazing and
showed me an awesome bug at this last
live hacking event
that utilized web cache deception which
is so cool and
It it was a
the ability for you to leak information
the path particularly the query
parameters
via web cache deception where it was it
was caching a 302 response
and that 302 response had the the the
you could force somebody to go to this
URL and it would cache their
query parameters
at that URL. So then you could visit
that same URL without the query
parameters and it would 302 you
to a certain URL with the query
parameters. So you could use that to
leak all sorts of stuff. And I was like
wow
that's lit.
Um
Web cache deception is one of those
things that I I have like not put almost
any research or time into like because
it's such a complicated thing and it it
feels like to me one of those things
that like you really have to have a
solid understanding and the right tools
and stuff and like know how to attack
and what to look for and I am not I
don't have those things yet but I would
I would really cool bug. I would
encourage you to just spend an hour on
it because I really it's not it's not
actually that
that crazy to do. And you've got access
to all those reports by Andre that I've
seen in the past where he like blew [__]
up with web cache deception. So go you
know, go read through those. It's not a
very intimidating vulnerability type
and there's a lot of weird wet edge
cases like this one that you'll see
where it's like
it's leaking some additional piece of
information or you have to do some weird
encoding to get it to work. But if you
can then it's a big dub and almost
always results in a high or critical
vulnerability. Um So that shout out to
Matumb Bear there. That one was super
duper cool.
Um
another one that I just kind of came up
with recently Joel that I hadn't really
thought about was this whole concept of
local storage poisoning.
Okay. So and this is what I mean by that
is like let's say you've got a gadget
that takes in your input from maybe like
query parameter hash or something like
that.
Stores it in a local storage you know,
cell
and then does something else with it,
right?
Yeah. Because you control
that whole thing
you can do a window.open to that page
poison that that local storage
cache and maybe you have to like get
some fine
fine tuning for like
when this race condition might work if
it does something later with it that's
bad. But then you can sort of race
condition and close that tab or redirect
that tab away and that that value that
you have in the local storage cell will
remain there.
And I think that's really cool and you
can use that to poison essentially you
know, a lot of times they'll be like um
uh
get local storage whatever or you know,
the two bars, right? Do XYZ, right? And
so then it'll use your cache value for
another thing and then you might be able
to insert yourself into a flow somewhere
in there. Um
Yeah, that's super creative.
I love that approach. I mean there's so
many things nowadays especially with
single page apps that
you know, local storage and session
storage are being used for.
I mean I think the biggest example for
me is like off tokens being stored in
session storage and local storage. It's
like
really insecure.
Yeah, I don't want to like it's really
insecure. Like there's no implicit
security mechanisms there that stop
anybody from reading it. Like you have
an XSS ATO done. Like
it's crazy. Yeah.
The interesting thing you mentioned
session storage. I did run into this
scenario as well the other day. So
session storage is limited to a specific
tab. Um
but it doesn't prevent us from doing
these sort of attacks because what you
can do is you can window.open
poison the session storage and then
window you know, that so like x equals
window.open x.location equals Yeah.
whatever to redirect it to a different
page and that's the same tab so the
session storage is going to be the same.
And you can still
storage is cross
cross origin cross every just within the
same tab and local storage is No no no.
It's it's it's local all of these are
segmented by origin. But um
but essentially you have a gadget you a
window.open some page on their website
where they put something they take your
input they put it into session storage
or whatever.
And then you redirect to a different
page on that same website same same tab
same origin So the session state
the session storage is going to be the
same and then it loads that from session
storage and does something with it.
You know, I've
once once again I said I've only
recently found it which means I haven't
really been looking for it for a long
time so I'm not really sure what
other
you know, how common this is but I have
seen it at least once in my career now.
So that's like like a one in
you know, 3000 applications.
Uh
hit rate. So it exists. Let's just say
it that. Let's just say that. It exists
and it'll be used and I I like that
scenario mentioned where it's like
reading by default from session storage
and then defaulting to some other value.
I see that a lot for sure. I can think
of multiple instances of that
that behavior. So that's something to
keep an eye out for sure.
Um next one. So we got two more. Cookie
injection and then context breaks which
is a bigger one. So let's cover cookie
injection real quick. Pretty simple
pretty straightforward. Can happen on
the server side with like a CRLF sort of
thing.
I saw someone
about the other day where you just
inject a semicolon into the the value
that's being set and then somehow some
weird server was like pushing it to the
next set cookie. So like you you know,
it'd be like some set value equals
something that you can control, right?
And then you terminate it midway and
then create a new one.
Normally you just put a semicolon and
then normally that would allow you to
specify like the domain and the path for
the thing which is cool but not really
helpful. And then but this one if you
did a semicolon it would just bump you
down into another set set cookie header.
Which is super weird and then you could
set your own cookie there. Um
So
very cool thing there on the server
side. But what we often see this as a as
a sink of sorts on the client side as
well where your user input is getting
put into a document.cookie equals
and then you can sort of poison a cookie
value from that scenario and there there
are scenarios where cookies are being
sort of echoed into the the response
body and this can result in XSS.
to say like you know, client side path
traversal XSS. There's a lot of
different you know, as a gadget there's
a lot of different pivot points from
there as well.
You know, especially with this one and
the last one that we just talked about
like session storage local storage
cookies. These are core core primitives
of web development and they're used in a
ton of places for a ton of different
things, right? When a developer has to
store something,
cross-session, cross-load, cross-page,
there are only so many mechanisms they
can use for that. And so, they're going
to end up using, you know, one of these
handful of mechanisms, and a lot of
times that's going to lead to other
behaviors that you can exploit somewhere
else within the page because they just
have to use it. Like there's only so
many mechanisms they can use. Mhm.
Absolutely. Yeah. I I think keeping an
eye on these is really good.
Okay, last one. And this is sort of a
catch-all, and I also want to talk about
some sort of conceptual stuff here.
So, this is
a gadget that I've named context breaks.
And this is sort of a catch-all category
that includes some of the stuff that we
mentioned before, but also just kind of
makes it a higher-level principle.
And the concept here is like, when can
you break out of the scenario that
you're supposed to be in? And and I
think
identifying these requires you to
understand what
context exists in the browser, which
means you need to be very familiar with
browser, you know, internals and such.
But an example of this, the most benign
example of this
is the one we talked about right before
this, which is cookie injection, right?
The scenario where you are able to set a
value for cookie, right? And then you're
able to set
take a semicolon
and break out of that value set and now
set an attribute of the cookie, right?
The path or the domain that follows the
cookie.
Your context has changed, right? You've
gone from a cookie value context to a
cookie attribute setting context.
And and I
Yeah, do you know off the top of your
head if in that context, for example,
what if what if what if I set like
um
same site none or same site strict or
what it like what if can if there's
multiple same sites? Like say the
server's already setting same site and I
and there's multiple set. Does it ignore
them? Does it
the first one is the one. So, I think we
should be able to override it. I That's
a good question. We should check that.
Um actually, I'll leave that as a as a
uh exercise for
exercise for the listeners, and please
drop the results into the Discord if you
get a chance. Yeah. But that that is a
really interesting question. I'm not I'm
not quite sure, but I think the that's
pretty much the most benign example of
it that I can think of is like that. But
even that should trigger something in
your brain, right? Oh,
context. Context breaking. I love
context breaking, you know. Um and and a
couple of the other examples I came up
with this is like CSS context, right? A
lot of times this is not going to be
very impactful. Um
but we talked about image injection and
stuff like that with like background
URL. You could do that with with CSS as
well. Um but being able to, you know,
semicolon break out of a CSS attribute
that's being defined or
um
sort of curly bracket break out of like
a CSS block, those are also changing
context, right? You're switching from a
CSS attribute
to uh
CSS attribute key
to I'm sorry, a CSS attribute value to a
CSS attribute key, or then if you're
able to use the curly bracket and break
out of that, now you're in a CSS sort of
global context where you can define
rules for all sorts of um various tags
and and IDs and that sort of thing.
Um Uh the another one that I came up
with This is another benign very benign
example. I've seen it result in XSS
before, but I was explaining to my
mentee why this is important the other
day. Uh it's the the third or fourth
bullet
fourth bullet down there, Joel, is
X breaking out of double quote uh
context in in JS. So, let's say you've
got a variable X equals a
uh double quote your input double quote.
And the double quote is escaped, and the
script tag is is escaped, right? Not
much you can do.
Is the backslash escaped? Because if you
can if you can do a backslash at the end
of that string, essentially what you've
done is you've unterminated that string.
And now that string is going to continue
until it sees another double quote.
And if you're have another input right
after that, you know, where Y equals
equals double quote your input double
quote, then you can then
terminate that
And start at Y.
Exactly. Now the double quote Now at the
start of the value where you're
injecting into Y, you're able to do like
plus and then alert one and then comment
out the rest of the string, and then
you're golden. You've got CSS execution.
Um and so anytime where you can affect
the flow of the context that they've
defined in the application, that is
freaking gold.
Yeah, and I love that perspective of
sort of like where you're breaking
context. It's like, you know, what where
is this intended this data intended to
be, right? Is it it's intended to be in
a cookie value. It's not intended to be
in the rest of the cookie. Or it's
intended to be within a CSS rule or
within a script tag or within a variable
attribute. But if you have some way to
break that context, to to you know,
modify the the context where that data
is being inserted or where it's being
evaluated from, those are really key
areas to focus your testing because
those are where you're going to pop your
bugs. That's where stuff's going wrong.
Um and so I I think that that really is
a great way to sort of sum it up and
highlight, you know, look for context
breaks. Look for look for areas where
your data is is is going beyond the
original intended context and being used
in some other way or being, you know,
interpreted in some other way, and find
a way to exploit that with other, you
know, other oracles, other gadgets,
other, you know, various
um you know, expectation techniques,
stuff that we've talked about today,
stuff that we've talked about on
previous episodes.
Yeah. Yeah, 100% and and Joel, I I think
I did a pretty decent job here of coming
up with common context breaks, but the a
couple of other ones that I kind of
wanted to throw in this list here was
um if you're able to inject This is sort
of a client-side path reversal sort of
scenario. If you're able to inject into
to a different part of the URL than you
were intended to. So, for example, if
you're able to do um essentially
parameter injection
on a back-end request. Let's say they
dynamically do a fetch request and you
one of your values is being provided as
a uh
as a
query parameter in that request. If
you're able to inject the ampersand
character and now specify another uh
query parameter or maybe even you're
able to
specify the hashtag parameter, and that
cuts off off all of the other parameters
that are on the right of that, then
you're breaking out of your normal
context. You go from a query parameter
value context to a query parameter key
context to a query parameter um you
know, to a hash context to all sorts of
these different levels.
Um And so, that's another really
impactful spot. And the the last one
that I had here was like and of course
you can do the same thing with the path
if you have access to the slash or
backslash character. And then um
the other one that I had here is sort of
if you're able to inject into context
that is
a uh a context that is being
JSON.parsed.
Um
you may be able to
do some sort of type confusion there
where you're supposed to be in a string
context, but you're in a array context
or in a in a um object context, and that
can have unintended application in the
application. Unintended application in
the application. Application Unintended
effect on the application. Um
I don't know, any other any other ones
come to mind there, Joel, that I might
have missed besides like the traditional
XSS and stuff like that?
Um I'm trying to think, but HTML
attribute context. I mean, but that's
Yeah, I mean, there's like a million
different
and you know, I think I'll defer to, you
know,
the whole like broader concept, which is
like looking for context breaks, like
you said, like identify the spots where
data is is moving outside of its
intended location and being either used
or interpreted or inserted or whatever
in a different place
either unintended or intended, and and
find a way to to leverage that to your
to your advantage either with gadgets or
some other type of vulnerability or
chaining it together. Yeah. I'll I'll
I'll add one more.
Let me see if I can find it.
That I just that I just thought of to
this is the meta tag
in Let's say for example, this is a long
shot, but this is another example of
like sort of nested context that could
this could be really interesting. In a
meta tag, if your input ends up in a
content security policy meta tag, the
content attribute of that tag is the
content security policy for that page.
So, now
you're in not only an HTML context, not
only an HTML attribute context, but
inside of that you're in a CSP
definition context. So, there's three
layers of syntax there, and every time
that syntax compounds, compounds,
compounds, the complexity increases for
them to be able to keep it secure. So,
you know, being able to use a semicolon
and define a different part of this the
content security policy, being able to
use a single quote inside of a double
quote HTML attribute context in this
scenario
on this content security policy
definition will allow you to define
various attributes.
So, all of these sort of especially
paying close attention, close close
attention to nested attributes. Just
like the cookie, right? The semicolon
there is nested inside the the
HTML
or the HTTP header attribute inside of
the set cookie attribute, and then now
we're getting into cookie metadata
attributes.
Um
Nested contexts, extremely dangerous.
Yeah, absolutely. Uh all right, man. I
know you got to bounce. All right, let's
let's cut it here, yeah?
Yeah, sounds good. That was that was
really good. Fun pod, dude. Fun pod.
Yeah, absolutely. All right, peace. All
right, catch you later. Peace.